{"name": "63D  2006-12", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. The Crossroads High School basketball team sponsored a student/faculty basketball game. Tickets sold for $5.00 each. Each person with a ticket was entitled to admission to the game, 1 pretzel, and 1 can of soda. Each additional pretzel cost $1.00 and each addition can of soda cost $1.50. The basketball team sold 120 tickets. At the game, 36 additional pretzels were sold. The team collected a total of $702.00. How many additional cans of soda were sold?", "choices": {"A": " 44", "B": " 48", "C": " 68", "D": " 92", "E": " 364"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2.  In football, total offense consists of  rushing  offense and passing offense. The table below shows rushing offense and total offense for a college football program during a 3-year period.In 1997, what was the number of yards of total offense that was passing offense?", "choices": {"A": " 1,532", "B": " 2,162", "C": " 2,275", "D": " 2,551", "E": " 2,664"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3.  A 7-day week is is how many times as long as 60 minutes?", "choices": {"A": " 24", "B": " 31", "C": " 52", "D": " 84", "E": " 168"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4.  Veata earns f dollars per hour for h hours and then earns g dollars per hour for 3h hours. In terms of f, g, and h, these earnings totaled how many dollars?", "choices": {"A": " 3fgh", "B": " 3fgh2 ", "C": " fh + 3g", "D": " fh + 3gh", "E": " 3fh + 3gh"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5.  A trapezoid is shown below with the given dimensions in meters. What is the area, in square meters, of the trapezoid?", "choices": {"A": " 9", "B": " 15", "C": " 18", "D": " 24", "E": " 48"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6.  The graph below shows the number of books checked out of the school library on the first 4 days of a 5-day week. How many books need to be checked out on Friday for the 5-day week's mean to equal the mean of the first 4 days?", "choices": {"A": " 0", "B": " 24", "C": " 30", "D": " 40", "E": " 120"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7.  A ball is kicked upward. It is h feet above the ground t seconds after it is kicked. The relationship between h and t is given by the equation h = 50t - 16t2. How many feet above the ground is the ball 2 seconds after it is kicked?", "choices": {"A": " 34", "B": " 36", "C": " 50", "D": " 68", "E": " 84"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. The high and low temperatures for a 5-day period are listed below. Which day had the greatest range of temperatures?", "choices": {"A": " Monday", "B": " Tuesday", "C": " Wednesday", "D": " Thursday", "E": " Friday"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9.  Siblings Peter, Paul, and Mary earned a total of $200 shoveling snow. If Peter earned 37% of the total and Paul earned $16, what fraction of the $200 did Mary earn?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": "", "E": " "}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10.  For f(x)\uff1d 2x \uff0b 10 and g(x) = 3x2, what is the value of f(g(-3)) ?", "choices": {"A": " 31", "B": " 48", "C": " 64", "D": " 108", "E": " 144"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. Each small square on the grid shown below has a side length of 1 cm. Each vertex of  the shaded  region lies on a vertex of a small square. What is  the area, in square centimeters, of the shaded region?", "choices": {"A": " 17", "B": " 23", "C": " 28", "D": " 29", "E": " 39"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12.  A roof rises 4\tfor each 12 inches\thorizontal run. This roof rises  inches in how many inches of horizontal run?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " 122"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13.  When a = 4 and b = -2,\t(2a - b) + ba \uff1d \uff1f", "choices": {"A": " -10", "B": " -6", "C": " 2", "D": " 22", "E": " 26"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. In the figure below, lines l and m are tangent to the\tcircle at points B and D, respectively. Points A and C are on the circle. The measure of \u2220ABC is 95\u00b0 and the measure of \u2220BCD is 85\u00b0.The lines in  which of the following pairs of lines are necessarily parallel?\u2160. l and m\u2161.  and \u2162.  and ", "choices": {"A": " \u2160only", "B": "\u2161 only", "C": "\u2162 only", "D": " \u2160 and \u2161 only", "E": " \u2160, \u2161, and \u2162"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15.  Each day, a grocery store sells 112 gallons of milk for $2.10 per gallon. The owner of the grocery store has determined that for each $0.03 increase in the price per gallon of milk, the number of gallons  sold  will decrease by 2. If x represents the number of $0.03 increases in the price of a gallon of milk, which of the following expressions represents the daily amount of money, in dollars, the grocery store will collect from the sale of milk?", "choices": {"A": " (2.10 - 0.03x)(112 - 2x)", "B": " (2.10 + 0.03x)(112 - 2x)", "C": " (2.10 + 0.03x)(112 - 0.02x)", "D": " (2.10 - 3x)(112 - 2x)", "E": " (2.10 + 3x)(112 - 2x)"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16.  The expression x2 + 5x - 6 is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": " (x - 6)(x + 1)", "B": " (x - 6)(x + 5)", "C": " (x - 3)(x - 2)", "D": " (x - 3)(x + 2)", "E": " (x - 1)(x + 6)"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17.  When a= 2 and b = 3, the expression ", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18.  The hours and minutes on a 12-hour digital clock are represented by 3 or 4 digits. Which of the following is the largest product that can be obtained by multiplying the digits in one of these representations?(Note: If the time is 8:45, the product of the digits is (8)(4)(5) = 160.)", "choices": {"A": " 90", "B": " 162", "C": " 405", "D": " 708", "E": " 729"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19.  The difference of 2 integers is 4. The sum of the same 2 integers is 38. What is the greater of the 2 integers?", "choices": {"A": " 17", "B": " 18", "C": " 19", "D": " 20", "E": " 21"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20.  In the figure below, the small isosceles right triangles are congruent. The area of the square is 225 square inches. What is the total area, in square inches, of the 2 small triangles?", "choices": {"A": " 75", "B": " 112.5", "C": " 150", "D": " 225", "E": " 450"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21.  To measure the height of a smokestack, Ariel places a mirror on level ground 80 feet from the base of the smokestack.   He then    forms   2   similar triangles looking into the mirror and backing up until  he sees the reflection of the top of the smokestack, as shown below. Ariel's eyes are 6 feet from the ground and he is 5 feet from the image in the mirror. Which of the following is closest to the height, in feet, of the smokestack?", "choices": {"A": " 110", "B": " 96", "C": " 91", "D": " 85", "E": " 67"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22.  For what value of x, if any, is the equation (x + 5)2 = (x + 1)2 true?", "choices": {"A": " -3", "B": " -1", "C": " 0", "D": " 3", "E": " There is no value of x for which the equation is true."}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23.  An equilateral  triangle,  with  the  coordinates  of 2 vertices labeled, is shown in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane below. Which of the following are the coordinates of the 3rd vertex?", "choices": {"A": " (0, m)", "B": " (m, m)", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24.  The diagonal of a square is  inches long. What is the area of the square, in square inches?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " 2", "C": " ", "D": " 4", "E": " "}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25.  In the figure below, AC represents a support wire x feet long. The wire is attached to a tower at C and to the ground at A. The distance between A and B, which is at the base of the tower, is 20 feet. The angle at A bas   measure \u03b8. Which of the following relationships must be true?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": "", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. The equation  is true for what real value of x?", "choices": {"A": " 9", "B": " 16", "C": " 25", "D": " 36", "E": " 64"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27.  In rectangle LMNP below, NP is  24 inches long and MN is 10 inches long. Points Q, R, and S are the midpoints of LP, LM, and MN, respectively. What is the perimeter, in inches, of pentagon NPQRS?", "choices": {"A": " 60", "B": " 68", "C": " 70", "D": " 120", "E": " 180"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. Use the following information to answer questions 28-30.The table below gives data about the population of the U.S. for 1990, 1995, and 1999.28. To the nearest percent, what percent of the total U.S. population in 1999 was male?", "choices": {"A": " 50%", "B": " 49%", "C": " 48%", "D": " 47%", "E": " 20%"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. Use the following information to answer questions 28-30.The table below gives data about the population of the U.S. for 1990, 1995, and 1999.29. The circle graph (pie chart) below represents the 1999 U.S. population distribution for the 4 regions listed. To the nearest degree, what is the measure of the central angle of the \"West\" sector?", "choices": {"A": " 81\u00b0", "B": " 76\u00b0", "C": " 68\u00b0", "D": " 40\u00b0", "E": " 22\u00b0"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. Use the following information to answer questions 28-30.The table below gives data about the population of the U.S. for 1990, 1995, and 1999.30. Expressed  in  millions  of  people,  what was  the average growth per year in total U.S. population from 1990 to 1995, rounded to the nearest 0.1 million?", "choices": {"A": " 2.8", "B": " 2.7", "C": " 2.0", "D": " 1.4", "E": " 1.0"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31.  Every camera lens has a measurement called the focal length, f, such that when an object is in focus, the distance  from  the  object to the  center  of  the  lens,  Do, and the distance from the center of the lens to the film, Di, satisfy  the equation . If the object is in focus, Do = 36 centimeters, and Di = 12 centimeters, what is the focal length of the lens, in centimeters?", "choices": {"A": " 3", "B": " 6", "C": " 9", "D": " 12", "E": " 24"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32.  What is the probability of randomly choosing a prime number from {2, 3, 4, 5, 6} ?", "choices": {"A": " 0", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33. For g(x,y) = 5x + 4y, what is the value of g(x,y) when  and x = 2 ?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " 16", "D": " 19", "E": " 28"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34.  What is the length, in coordinate units, of a diagonal of the rectangle that has (0,3), (4,3), and (4,0) as 3 of its vertices in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane?", "choices": {"A": " 3", "B": " 4", "C": " 5", "D": " 6", "E": " 7"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35.  What is the value of x if log5 x = 2 ?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " 10", "D": " 25", "E": " 100"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. The fuel remaining in the gas tank of a particular car that starts with a full 16-gallon tank of gas can be approximated by the equation y = 16 - 0.05x, where x is the number of miles the car has traveled for 0 \u2264 x \u2264 320, and y is the number of gallons remaining in the tank. According to this equation, which of the following statements is true about this car?", "choices": {"A": " In traveling 0.05 miles, the car uses 1 gallon of gas.", "B": "In traveling 1 mile, the car uses 0.05 gallon of gas.", "C": " In traveling 16 miles, the car uses 0.05 gallon of gas.", "D": " In traveling 16 miles, the car uses 1 gallon of gas.", "E": " In traveling 80 miles, the car uses 16 gallons of gas."}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. A formula for the volume of a right circular cone with its  top  removed  is , where  R and r are radii and h is height, as shown in the figure below.The number of cubic feet of wood in a tree stump can be estimated using the formula given. About how many cubic feet of wood are there in the tree stump shown below?", "choices": {"A": " 12", "B": " 18", "C": " 19", "D": " 38", "E": " 77"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38.  Which of the following is the set of real solutions for the equation 6x + 10 = 2(3x + 5) ?", "choices": {"A": " The empty set", "B": " ", "C": " {0}", "D": " {0, 1}", "E": " The set of all real numbers"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. The expression  equals:", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. The  figure  below  shows  a  circular garden  surrounded by a circular drive. The outside circle of the drive has a diameter of 100 meters and the  drive  has a  uniform width  of  12  meters.  Which  of  the  following is closest to the area, in square meters, of the garden?", "choices": {"A": " 240", "B": " 310", "C": " 4,500", "D": " 7,900", "E": " 18,000"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. For all nonzero real  numbers x and y,  what  is the  value of x0 + y0 ?", "choices": {"A": " 2", "B": " 1", "C": " 0", "D": " x + y", "E": " Undefined"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42.  In the  figure below,  LM = MA,  and A, B,  C, and D are on ME. Of the angles \u2220LAM, \u2220LBM, \u2220LCM, \u2220LDM, and \u2220LEM, which one has the smallest sine?", "choices": {"A": " \u2220LAM", "B": " \u2220LBM", "C": " \u2220LCM", "D": " \u2220LDM", "E": " \u2220LEM"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43.  Use the following information to answer questions 43-45.The graph of y = f(x) is shown in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane below with 5 points labeled.43. Which of the following points is the y-intercept of the graph of y = f(x) ?", "choices": {"A": " P", "B": " Q", "C": " R", "D": " S", "E": " T"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. Use the following information to answer questions 43-45.The graph of y = f(x) is shown in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane below with 5 points labeled.44. The function y = f(x) can be classified as one of the following types of functions. Which one is it?", "choices": {"A": " Constant", "B": " Linear", "C": " Quadratic", "D": " Cubic", "E": " Trigonometric"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. Use the following information to answer questions 43-45.The graph of y = f(x) is shown in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane below with 5 points labeled.45. Which of the  following  graphs  is  the reflection  of y = f(x) across the line y = x ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46.  If x is a factor of 35 and y is a factor of 16, the product of x and y could NOT be which of the following?", "choices": {"A": " 1", "B": " 24", "C": " 40", "D": " 112", "E": " 560"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47.  For each positive integer n, let ne be the product of all positive even numbers less than or equal to n. For example, 6e=(6)(4)(2) = 48 and 7e = (6)(4)(2) = 48. What is the value of  ?", "choices": {"A": " 384", "B": " 1,280", "C": " 1,920", "D": " 15,360", "E": " 23,040"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48.  If (1,b) is on the graph of the equation x - 3y = 7 in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, then b = ?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " -2", "C": " 2", "D": " 3", "E": " 6"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. For all x &gt; 0, what happens to the value of , as x increases?", "choices": {"A": "It decreases in proportion to x2.", "B": " It decreases in proportion to x.", "C": " It increases in proportion to x.", "D": " It increases in proportion to x2.", "E": " It remains constant."}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50.  In the figure below, B is on AD and the angle measures are as given. What is the degree measure of \u2220ABC ?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " 25\u00b0"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51.  In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, what is the slope of a line passing through the points (-1,-8) and (0,6) ?", "choices": {"A": " -14", "B": " -2", "C": " ", "D": " 2", "E": " 14"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52.  What is the degree measure of an angle that measures  radians?", "choices": {"A": " 15\u00b0", "B": " 75\u00b0", "C": " 150\u00b0", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53.  A circle in  the standard  (x,y)  coordinate  plane has its center at (2,6) and an area of 4\u03c0 square coordinate units. Which  of  the following  is an equation for this circle?", "choices": {"A": " (x - 6)2 - (y - 2)2 = 16", "B": "(x - 6)2 + (y - 2)2 = 4", "C": " (x - 6)2 + (y - 2)2 = 16", "D": " (x - 2)2 + (y - 6)2 = 4", "E": " (x - 2)2 + (y - 6)2 = 16"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54.  Which of the following is FALSE for some x and y that satisfy  the equation  ?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " x = y", "C": " x2 + y2 = 2xy", "D": " x2 = y2", "E": " x5 + y5 = 1"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55.  The 2 \u00d7 3 matrix  represents \u25b3ABC with vertices A(-2,1), B(1 ,2), and C(3,-2) in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane. After a translation  of \u25b3ABC, the   matrix representing    the translated   triangle is . What is the value of k ?", "choices": {"A": " -1", "B": " -2", "C": " -3", "D": " -4", "E": " -5"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56.  Three different logical operators are defined in the table below.The logic diagram below uses the  3  operators. The only possible values for a, b, c, and d are 0 and 1. Which  of the following  (a,b,c,d) inputs will result in an output of 1 ?", "choices": {"A": " (0, 1, 0, 0)", "B": " (0, 1, 1, 1)", "C": " (1, 0, 1, 0)", "D": " (1, 1, 0, 0)", "E": " (1, 1, 0, 1)"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57.  Whenever b &gt; 0, which of the following real number line   graphs   represents the to solution for x to the inequality I x + b I \u2265 4 ?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58.  Whenever   m   and   n   are   both   integers,\twhat is (5.0 X 10m)(8.0 x 10n) expressed in scientific notation?", "choices": {"A": " 4.0 \u00d7 10mn", "B": " 4.0 \u00d7 10m+n+1", "C": " 40.0 \u00d7 10mn", "D": " ", "E": " 40.0 \u00d7 100mn"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59.  The points A, B, C, and D lie in that order on a straight line. The midpoint of AC is B, and the midpoint of AD is C. The length of AB is  x inches, and  the  length  of CD is 3x  -  6 inches. What is the length,  in inches,  of AD\uff1f", "choices": {"A": " 24", "B": " 16", "C": " 12", "D": " 8", "E": " 6"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. The  circle shown  below  has  a radius  of  10  cm.  A central angle with measure 18\u00b0 intercepts minor arc . How many centimeters long is minor arc   ?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " \u03c0", "D": " ", "E": " 180\u03c0"}, "correct": "C"}]}